There are two sides to every family.
Brothers is a drama, thriller, war film directed by Jim Sheridan.
When his helicopter goes down during his fourth tour of duty in
Afghanistan, Marine Sam Cahill is presumed dead.
Back home, brother Tommy steps in to look over
Sam’s wife, Grace, and two children.
Sam’s surprise homecoming triggers domestic mayhem.
Capt. Sam Cahill, played by Tobey Maguire.
Tommy Cahill, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Grace Cahill, played by Natalie Portman.
Hank Cahill, played by Sam Shepard.
Elsie Cahill, played by Mare Winningham.
Isabelle Cahill, played by Bailee Madison.
Brothers is a 2009 American psychological thriller film directed
by Jim Sheridan and written by David Benioff.
The film is a remake of the 2004 Danish film by Susanne Bier, and both
films take inspiration from the epic poem Odyssey by Homer.
The film stars Tobey Maguire, Jake Gyllenhaal, Natalie Portman, Sam
Shepard, Clifton Collins Jr., and Mare Winningham.
The film follows Captain Sam Cahill, a USMC officer who is captured by the
Taliban after he is presumably killed in the war in Afghanistan.
Upon being rescued and reunited with his brother Tommy and wife Grace, he
suffers from severe PTSD as he struggles to reintegrate into society.
Brothers was theatrically released in the United States on December 4, 2009, by Lionsgate, and
received mixed reviews from critics, although Maguire's acting was praised.
The film grossed $45 million against a $26 million budget.
The film was nominated for Best Actor for Maguire and Best Original Song for
"Winter", performed by U2, at the 67th Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship, loss of loved one,
brother-in-law, afghanistan war (2001-2021), remake.
The tone is emotional and intense.